Black Diamond is a thriller film directed by Judd Bloch.
Follows a young woman whose idyllic life with her hedge funder boyfriend turns it into a deadly
triangle of lust, obsession and murder after meeting a local cowboy handyman.
Elena, played by Inbar Lavi.
Spencer, played by Ray Panthaki.
Jesse, played by Jake McLaughlin.
Teft, played by Shaun Sipos.
Tomas, played by Michael James Bell.
Cop #1, played by Tristan Cunningham.
Blood Diamond is a 2006 American political war thriller film directed and co-produced by Edward
Zwick and starring Leonardo DiCaprio, Jennifer Connelly, and Djimon Hounsou.
The title refers to blood diamonds, which are diamonds mined in war zones and sold to finance
conflicts, and thereby profit warlords and diamond companies around the world.
Set during the Sierra Leone Civil War of 1991–2002, the film depicts a country torn
apart by the struggle between government loyalists and insurgent forces.
It also portrays many of the atrocities of that war, including the rebels' amputation of
civilians' hands to discourage them from voting in upcoming elections.
The film's ending, in which a conference is held concerning blood diamonds, refers to a
historic meeting that took place in Kimberley, South Africa, in 2000.
It led to development of the Kimberley Process Certification Scheme, which sought to certify the origin of rough diamonds in order
to curb the trade in conflict diamonds; the certification scheme has since been mostly abandoned as ineffective.
The film received positive reviews, with praise directed
toward the performances of DiCaprio and Hounsou.
The film grossed $171 million worldwide and received five Oscar nominations,
including Best Actor for DiCaprio and Best Supporting Actor for Hounsou.
DiCaprio received a nomination for a Golden Globe Award for Best Actor – Motion Picture
Drama (also nominated that year in the same category for The Departed).
In addition, DiCaprio and Hounsou were nominated for Outstanding Male Actor in a Leading Role and
Outstanding Male Actor in a Supporting Role at the 13th Screen Actors Guild Awards.
The tone is lighthearted and intense.